Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/alexlaurant (LinkedIn) www.alexlaurant.net/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Art Direction
Concept Design
Conceptual Art

Languages Italian

Alex Laurant

Artistic & Creative Director

Kirkland, Washington, United States

Summary

Creative Director, Art director, visual / concept designer and multidisciplinary chameleon - across a spectrum of screen-based and immersive media and platforms. Bringing more than two decades of artistic and creative leadership, visual design & illustration to MR/VR/AR experiences, video games, feature films, commercials, theater & print.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS:

- Mixed/Virtual Reality: Meta Avatar futurism, Microsoft HoloLens incubation and product dev
- Immersive/XR Narrative Experience Innovation HBO Interactive studio
- Videogames: EA, Sony, LucasArts Harry Potter & the Goblet of Fire, Crysis, Escape Plan
- Film VFX: ILM, Warner Bros, Reliance Minority Report, The Mummy, The Day After Tomorrow

Website: https://www.alexlaurant.net/

Contact: lxl1@comcast.net

Experience

Self-employed

Art Director / Creative Director / Visual Development-Concept Artist April 2023 - Present (1 month)

Kirkland, Washington, United States

Studio LXL

Art Director/Concept Illustrator/Production Design Consultant September 2009 - Present (13 years 8 months)

Seattle & San Francisco

Art and Creative direction, concept design, illustration, visual development, production design at the intersections of the tech, entertainment and emerging media industries: XR, games, film, animation, VFX, TV, advertising, LBE and theater.

Meta

Creative Director March 2022 - April 2023 (1 year 2 months)

Greater Seattle Area

Studio Wildcard
Art Director
May 2020 - April 2022 (2 years)
Seattle, Washington, United States

https://store.steampowered.com/app/346110/ARK_Survival_Evolved/https://youtu.be/587ZD-y4LQE

HBO

Director of Artistic Design May 2019 - April 2020 (1 year)

Greater Seattle Area

I led the visual side of the interactive/immersive team at HBO's Digital Products group, with the mission to redefine the modern entertainment experience. We collaborated with award winning creators to explore new avenues of interactive media, through multiple platforms, devices, and storytelling paradigms – from the evolutionary to the experimental.

- Directed and contributed to art and visual design for our internal R&D team's projects.
- Managed and directed art efforts for our Publishing team, partnering with external development studios on shipping products (e.g. games & other interactive narrative experiences)
- Supported internal company promotion & evangelism, authored industry research presentations, and lead the recruiting/hiring push to build up our internal Art capabilities.

Microsoft

7 years 6 months

Principal Art Director - WindowsNEXT December 2016 - November 2018 (2 years) Redmond, WA

WindowsNEXT: MICROSOFT PHOTOS & VIDEO APP

Principal Art Director for the team refreshing the Photos app for PC, including adding a new video editor and 3D special effects tools while also refining and updating the entire app's UI and UX. Evolved the product's brand through a new illustration/animation style.

Principal Art Director - HoloLens Development & Experiences Studio June 2011 - November 2018 (7 years 6 months)

Redmond, WA

HOLOLENS DEVELOPMENT & Showcase Experiences Studio:

Directed all art, visual design, VFX and art asset production for the team's HoloLens immersive experience prototypes, demos and shipped products, partnering closely across creative and technical disciplines, while contributing to experience, UX/UI and narrative design. Served as a key creative, visual designer, production designer and VFX supervisor on products, prototypes, envisioning and marketing videos and demos. Designed and drove the visual branding for the studio and its products.

Float Hybrid Entertainment Art Director/Concept Illustrator January 2011 - May 2011 (5 months) San Francisco

SQUISHBOT - Kinect game

Helped shape the visual style and led visual development of key environments, props and animation for this (ultimately unreleased) game for the KINECT platform.

FilmDistrict
Creative / Art Director
2011 - 2011 (less than a year)
Greater Los Angeles Area

Theatrical logo bumper

Designed and art directed a 17-second theatrical logo ident for the new production & distribution studio, produced by Marjolaine Tremblay, with VFX created by RodeoFX in Montreal (score composed by James Newton Howard).

Sony

Concept Illustrator / Designer - FunBits Interactive 2010 - 2011 (1 year)

Greater Seattle Area

ESCAPE PLAN (for Sony Playstation VITA))

Created concept designs and illustrations for numerous environments, game mechanics, gags and narrative moments for Seattle developer Fun Bits Interactive, for their 2011 VITA platformer created for the VITA handheld device.

Reliance MediaWorks Ltd.

Sr. Art Director, Matte Painter, Digital Artist 2009 - July 2010 (1 year)

San Francisco Bay Area

THE CONSPIRATOR (feature - directed by Robert Redford)

Designed and Art Directed all aspects of VFX design and execution; including pitch-packages and bids, designing shots, color concept artwork and previsualization, final matte paintings and effects assets.

Warner Brothers Pictures
Senior Concept Illustrator
March 2009 - September 2009 (7 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

GREEN LANTERN

Concept illustrator in the Warner Bros production dept, contributing a wide range of visual concepts for key environments, ships, characters and sequences for the Green Lantern feature.

LucasArts
Art Director
October 2006 - February 2009 (2 years 5 months)
San Francisco

INTERNAL STORY & GAME INCUBATION STUDIO

Helped build and lead a secret incubation team charged by George Lucas to conceive his next original franchise, to be launched as a console game. For 2+ years built and directed a team of 25+ 2D and 3D artists, TV writers and game designers developing and pitching dozens of game/story concepts.

Supervised blue-sky brainstorm sessions, researched and developed style explorations, wrote pitch-briefs, authored visual design guidelines for the team, documented processes to support our engineers, designers and producers. Year 2 was spent developing the selected concept, but the project was shelved with the 2008 recession.

Electronic Arts, UK Studio Senior Art Director August 2004 - July 2006 (2 years) London, United Kingdom

HARRY POTTER & THE GOBLET OF FIRE (PS2 GAME)

Directed a style overhaul for the 4th game in EA's successful Potter franchise, raising the visual quality bar for this more mature-themed release. Defined the style, lighting, characters and worlds and UI, amplifying the cinematic

language and developing new creatures and environments while remaining true to the spirit of both J.K. Rowling's fiction and the films' visual aesthetic.

Served as Central Studio Art Director for several games and initiatives, consulting Art Director/Concept Artist for Crytek's widely acclaimed PC game Crysis; supported 'EA European Partners' external publishing group, directed animation studios in India, and lead a new I.P. incubation initiative.

Industrial Light & Magic Senior Visual Effects Art Director & Concept Artist March 1996 - August 2004 (8 years 6 months) San Francisco Bay Area

Responsible for design and art direction of film and commercial visual effects at all stages of production, working in close collaboration with directors, production designers, CG and VFX supervisors and large production teams.

Created numerous artwork pitch packages, developed concepts with studios/directors/production designers, designed digital and practical sets, storyboards, final concept artwork, and 2D / 3D pre-visualization.

Managed art teams, supervised miniature and stage sets and character maquettes, art directed creation of digital characters, environments, matte paintings, miniatures and final shot compositing.

ILM Filmography:

2004 THE DAY AFTER TOMORROW

2003 PETER PAN

2002 MINORITY REPORT

2002 STAR WARS EPISODE 2 ATTACK OF THE CLONES

2001 THE MUMMY RETURNS

2000 MISSION TO MARS

1999 THE MUMMY

1999 THE BFG

1998 FRANKENSTEIN (bid)

1997 SAVING PRIVATE RYAN

1997 CONTACT

1997 DEEP IMPACT

1996 RETURN OF THE JEDI, Special Edition

1996 EMPIRE STRIKES BACK, Special Edition

Rocket Science Games Art Director 1996 - 1996 (less than a year) San Francisco Bay Area

Acting Art Director for the Mac & PC game OBSIDIAN.

Albathion Software, Inc. Art Director, artist, animator 1991 - 1996 (5 years)

Interactive Multimedia design and production:

Educational interactive products for science museums, such as The Exploratorium in SF.

Corporate clients included Lifecan/Johnson & Johnson.

Developed educational adventure game prototype for Broderbund Software.

Won Multimedia award for Childrens' "Mother Goose" educational software title published by Mattel Media

Freelance Illustration & Graphic Designer Illustrator, Graphic Designer 1987 - 1991 (4 years)
San Francisco

Corporate and promotional graphic design, advertising and editorial illustration for magazines, newspapers, books and posters.

Education

California College of the Arts

BA, Graphic design, drawing, printmaking, painting, illustration · (1982 - 1987)

SACI (Studio Art Centers International), Florence
Bachelor of Art, Fine art, art history, language, food and Chianti · (1985 - 1986)